

SHAMIM REZA Software Engineer

01930269567 shamim.reza2292@gmail.com shamimreza2292.github.io/portfolio/ Dhaka, Bangladesh

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Metatude Asia LTD | Uttara, Dhaka, Bangladesh 10/2019 - Present

- Responsible for Front-End & MEAN Stack web development.
- Serious passion for UI effects, animations and creating intuitive, dynamic user experiences (UX).
- Build Backend and Frontend web application using Node.js, Express.js, MySql, Angular, HTML5 & CSS3.

Software Engineer

DG Innovation Lab | Gulshan, Dhaka, Bangladesh 08/2017 - 09/2019

- Writing JavaScript, CSS3(SASS) & HTML5
- Developing product analysis tasks. Making complex technical and design decisions for Angular projects.
- Developing SPA application codes and unit tests in Angular, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB to create RESTful web application.

Frontend Developer

Developer People | Uttara, Dhaka, Bangladesh 05/2016 - 07/2017

- Involved in development of the frontend applications using web technologies like HTML5 and CSS3.
- Built Web pages that are more user-interactive by using jQuery plugins, jqValidtor, AutoComplete, AJAX, JSON, AngularJS and JavaScript.

EDUCATION

Electrical and Electronics Engineering

Bachelor of Science

2016 -

International university of Business Agriculture and Technology | Dhaka, Bangladesh

Science

Millstone School & college | Dhaka, Bangladesh 2010 -

Higher Secondary School

Science

Dulai High School | Pabna, Bangladesh 2008 -Secondary School

SUMMARY

Last 4 years I worked for some software companies which were foreign ownership. I was responsible for Front-End & MEAN Stack web development. I have a serious passion for UI effects, animations and creating intuitive, dynamic user experiences (UX).I build Back-End and Front-End web application using Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Angular, HTML5 & CSS3. Within some project I am only responsible for creating RESTfull API using Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB and Postman for testing API EndPoint.

SKILLS

JavaScript

Angular

React.js

React Native

TypeScript

Node.js

MongoDB

MySql

Html5

Css3

Ajax

Figma

Jira

Git/Version Control

GitHub/Bitbucket

LANGUAGES

English

Intermediate